hello everyone this is Richard with
hydrogen technology today comm I'm going
to revisit this video series just to
talk a little bit about my cell and how
it operates with the configuration we've
spoke about in the past couple of videos
in my pickup truck and you know what
what formula I use for my electrolyte
and things of that nature a little bit
about what you're looking at here this
is just basically a container from
Walmart you know it's a sort of like a
mason jar but it's plastic and I can
drill through it you can see I've got my
my nipple Barb here this is 3/8 and I've
got a positive negative connection
coming out of there it's all sealed up
with I don't use any silicone sealer
those are just rubber washers
I've got about 16 ounces of water
there's mineral water or distilled water
and I've got just a little less than a
quarter teaspoon of sodium hydroxide
this stuff right here that's from Lowe's
but eight dollars a jar it'll last
pretty much forever we're gonna pull 12
volts this cell has been conditioned so
meaning it's been ran before many times
and it's ready to pretty much what you
see it draws what its going to draw
forever as far as amperage goes I'm
going to go ahead and turn the cell on
show you at a Ford f-150 a 2003 with the
Triton 5 4 liter engine what I do what I
use for hydrogen in my truck and and
here we go just going to turn it on and
we're on
you can pretty much bet that's I've
measured that before that's right around
two liters a minute
little less we're pulling just over 20
amps the water does warm up a little bit
little more than I'd like I need to
rebuild my pulse width modulator to drop
that down to around 15 amps because I'm
really throwing out a little more
hydrogen than my truck needs for an
assisted fuel cell but that's my setup
we'll go to the truck and I'll show you
how I've got it all wired in